Register of the Indian Subject Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Indian Subject collection,
1930-2003
XX864
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, election campaign literature, and other printed matter, relating to political, social and economic conditions in India, and to elections in India.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat to find the full extent of the collection.
Scope and Content Note
Pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, election campaign literature, and other printed matter, relating to political, social and economic conditions in India, and to elections in India.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Elections--India.; India--Politics and government.; India--History--1947-
Series Description
- Political Parties File, 1977-2003. (Box 1-3)
  Bulletins, election manifestos, fliers, journals, newsletters, pamphlets, and publications, primarily in English, sponsored by different political parties to promote their respective political ideologies, arranged alphabetically by name of party
- Printed Matter, 1930-1985. (Box 3)
  Bulletins, pamphlets, papers, and reports on various subjects prepared by individuals and political organizations, arranged chronologically
- Memorabilia, n.d. (Box 3)
  Wooden plaques depicting Mahatma Gandhi and Sarojini Naidu
Container List
- POLITICAL PARTIES FILE, 1977-2003 (Box 1)
  - All India Congress Committee (I), journal, 2003 June (Folder 1: 1)
  - Hindustan Gadar Party, flier, n.d. (Folder 1: 2)
  - Janata Dal
    - Bulletins, 1978-1989 (Folder 1: 3)
    - Collection of articles from the journal Janata Dal Patrika, 1998 (Folder 1: 4)
    - Election manifestos, 1996-1998 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Pamphlets and newsletter (Box 2)
      - Undated (Folder 2: 1)
      - 1979-1998 (Folder 2: 2)
    - Publications
      - Congress (I)'s Double Standards on Property and Respect for the Judiciary, study, Karnataka Legislature Janata Party, Bangalore, India, n.d. (Folder 2: 3)
      - Constitution of the Janata Party, 1977 December 21; Janata Era: First Year, 1978 May 1; Janata Era: Second Year, 1979 May 1; and A Black Paper on Conspiracy Against the People, 1979 August (Folder 2: 4)
      - Evolution of Socialist Policy in India, edited by Surendra Mohan, Hari Dev Sharma, Vinod Prasad Singh, and Sunilam, 1997 November (Folder 2: 5)
  - National Front, manifesto, 1991 May (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Nationalist Congress Party, pamphlets, n.d. (Folder 3: 2)
  - United Front, pamphlets, n.d. (Folder 3: 3)
    Includes a typescript copy
- PRINTED MATTER, 1930-1985
  - "Towards 2000: Minimum Programme for National Regeneration," paper presented by a Group of Concerned Citizens, n.d. (Folder 3: 4)
  - Indian Events, bulletin, 1930 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Indo-British Big Business Deals, Arun Bose, pamphlet, 1947 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Die Wirtschaftsethik des Hinduismus und der Kommunismus, Erik Turnwald, pamphlet, 1967. (Folder 3: 7)
    In German
  - Goa, pamphlet, 1971 December. (Folder 3: 8)
    In Portuguese
  - Oppression in Punjab, a report to the nation by Citizens for Democracy, with a foreword by V. M. Tarkunde and preface by George Fernandes, 1985 October (Folder 3: 9)
- MEMORABILIA, n.d.
  - Wooden plaques depicting Mahatma Gandhi and Sarojini Naidu (Folder 3: 10)